Finding Aid for the Los Angeles Unified School District Board of Education Records LSC.1923
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Subject Files, 1913-2012
  - Employment, 1962-1996 (Box 1255, Folder 1-2, Box 1709, Box 1247, Box 1248, Box 1249, Box 1250, Box 1251, Box 1252, Box 1253, Box 1254)
    1,254: Joint Powers Agreement establishing the EYOA, reconstitution of EYOA into the Greater Los Angeles Community Action Agency, Project First Break Annual Report, Youth Opportunities Unlimited Board Reports, Fair Employment Practice Commission newsletters (1963-1996).
    1,255: Report on Watts Skill Center, Negro charges of funding discrimination against the Watts Skill Center, Skill Centers Program Report prepared by the Skill Center Investigating Committee, Watts Skill Center Student questions to the Board in protest of educational inequities, "Skill Center News" (1966-1996).
    1,709: MDTA Communications from the Division of Adult Education, Skill Center News and Specially Funded Programs in Adult Education Report (1966-1971).
  - Energy Management System, 1985 October 21-2001 September 25 (Box 1255, Folder 3-4)
    Approvals of proposals for Environmental Control Systems.
  - Energy Services Requirements, 2000 February 22-2008 September 23 (Box 1255, Folder 5)
    Authorizations to front fund Energy Services Requirements Contracts.
  - English Immersion, 1998 July 23-2002 January 8 (Box 1255, Folder 6)
    Committee Reports concerning the Structured English Immersion Program, authorization to teach limited English proficient students, Proposition 227 implementation updates and Proposition 227 implementation questions and answers.
  - English Language Acquisition Program, 2000 September 12 (Box 1255, Folder 7)
    Proposal that the Board authorize staff to submit the California Department of Education funding application for the English Language Application Program (ELAP).
  - English Language Learners, 2002-1999 (Box 1255, Folder 8-9)
    Master Plan Evaluation Report for English Language Learners (ELL), Curriculum and Instruction Committee Reports regarding Structured English Immersion and Stanford 9 accommodations for ELLs.
  - Enrollment, 1978 May 15-2004 October 22 (Box 1256, Box 1257)
    Average Daily Attendance and Enrollment by Schools, tabulation of schools and grades according to enrollment and classification, enrollment reports, "White Pupils Decline By 19,088 In Los Angeles School District" press release, comparisons of norm day enrollments by grade level and local district, enrollment projections, Enrollment Committee reports, Priority Housing "Options to Increase Capacity at Secondary Schools" report, "Enrollment of Students Returning From Juvenile Justice Facilities and Other Placements" bulletin and student integration Joint Enrollment Program (JEP) Board Communication.
  - Entertainment, 1948 December 17-1966 November 18 (Box 1258, Folder 1)
    Policies regarding entertainment and educational programs in the schools, correspondence from students asking that the Intergroup Cultural Awareness Program be continued and reference guides for qualified elementary school entertainment/educational programs.
  - Enterprise Resource Planning, 2004-2005 (Box 1258, Folder 2)
    Enterprise Resource Planning Audit Business Technology Resource Book.
  - Environmental Education, 1979 May 14-1994 December 9 (Box 1258, Folder 3-5)
    Inter-office correspondence and reports on the Environmental Education and Recycling Center Project, Environmental Education and the Environmental/Energy Education Grant Project.
  - Environmental Hazards, 1999 September 28 (Box 1258, Folder 6-7)
    "Investigative Report: Monitoring Environmental Hazards at LAUSD" conducted by Public Interest Investigations, Inc. (PII). This investigation was conducted after the Board terminated the employment of the District's Director of the Environmental Health and Safety Branch, Hamid Arabzadeh. On July 28, 1998, Arabzadeh appeared before the Board to protest his termination and made over 40 allegations during his testimony. The investigation focused on Arabzadeh's allegations in three general areas: That the District engaged in an ongoing campaign of cover-up and concealment of serious environmental hazards and problems, that the District ignored the advice of its own staff to conduct adequate environmental testing of the area surrounding Jefferson Middle School and that the District mishandled the environmental problems at the Belmont Learning Complex project, cutting the Environmental Health and Safety Branch out of the process.
  - Environmental Impact Report, 1978 September 18-2008 December 9 (Box 1259, Box 1260, Box 1261)
    Environmental Impact Reports (EIRs), Reports of Findings and Statements of Overriding Considerations, Comments and Responses to Reports, Crawford v. Board of Education Draft EIR for Plan for the Integration of Pupils, Public Hearing Transcripts, EIR Draft for Baldwin Hills Stocker Street/Valleyridge Housing Development, Final EIR for the Belmont New Elementary School No. 6, Los Angeles Times article, "L.A. Unified Rushed Its Environmental Studies, Critics Say," Belmont Learning Complex Final EIR, Mitigation Monitoring Plan and Addendum to the Final EIR for Proposed Dorothy Johnson New Opportunity High School (Previously Jefferson New Senior High School No. 1 Site), West Los Angeles Veloway Project EIR, Draft EIR for Greenwich West Development, Draft EIR for Freeway Development Project No. 1 Amendment No. 3 and Lynwood Regional Justice Center Draft EIR.
  - Environmental Legislative Policy, 1999 July 6 (Box 1262, Folder 1)
    Proposal that the Board adopt Principles and Legislative Guidelines with respect to the general policy of the District regarding environmental legislation.
  - Ephebian Society, 1947-1958 (Box 1262, Folder 2)
    The Ephebian Society, founded in February of 1918 as a civic service organization by Dr. Albert Shiels, restricted its membership to graduates of Los Angeles City high schools chosen on the basis of scholastic and service records in the ratio of one to each forty graduates. Materials include correspondence between the Board and the Ephebian Society, The Athenian Ephebic Oath of Allegiance in American Schools and Colleges by Fletcher Harper Swift and "The Torch," the official publication of the Ephebian Society of Los Angeles.
  - Epidemics, 1932-2009 (Box 1262, Folder 3-5)
    Summarized Statement of Days of Absence of Pupils Due To Influenza and Other Respiratory Infections During 1940-41 Epidemic Period, Procedures for the Control of Major Communicable Diseases in the Schools, correspondence, consent forms and reports concerning smallpox and diptheria vaccinations, "A Chance For Life" Annual Report of the Los Angeles Tuberculosis And Health Association, Bulletin on the Control of Infantile Paralysis, Memoranda on Swine Flu Preparedness in Schools and "Pandemic Flu: How To Stay Well" video.
    Includes 1 DVD.
    Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. To access audiovisual materials you must notify the reference desk in advance of your visit.
  - Equal Access Act 1984, 1984 October 15 (Box 1262, Folder 6)
    Bulletin concerning the Equal Access Act, passed by Congress in 1984, making it unlawful for any public secondary school receiving federal financial assistance to deny equal access to facilities for voluntary student initiated meetings regardless of the nature or content of such meetings so long as the meetings are otherwise lawful.
  - Equal Rights Amendment, 1975 July 14-1980 October 2 (Box 1262, Folder 7)
    Board motions and resolutions in support of the Equal Rights Amendment and a copy of a "Women's Rights Consent Decree."
  - Equipment, 1930-2008 (Box 1262, Folder 8-10, Box 1263, Box 1264, Box 1265, Box 1266, Box 1267)
    Correspondence, brochures, petitions, newsletters, policies, lists, purchase orders, reports concerning equipment loans, purchases, obsolescence, sales, insurance, agreements, contracts, storage, delivery and including War Surplus Property.
  - E-Rate, 1998 March 9-2008 April 22 (Box 1268, Folder 1)
    Authorizations and reports concerning the E-Rate Program and its discounted products and services.
  - Escutia Project, 1998 November 10-2005 October 11 (Box 1268, Folder 2)
    Facilities Committee Reports concerning the Martha Escutia Primary Center, previously known as Corona New Primary Center.
  - Ethics Policy, 1998 September 24-2006 November 14 (Box 1268, Folder 3-4)
    Special Review and reports related to the District's ethics policy statement, adoption of a code of ethics and ethics program which consists of five major components: ethics code, training, advice, compliance and continuous improvement.
  - Ethnic Survey, 1991-1992 (Box 1268, Folder 5)
    Executive Summary of the Fall 1991 Ethnic Survey Report produced by the Information Technology Division highlights the ethnic distribution of students and staff and provides a historical overview of ethnic trends on colored graphs.
  - Evacuation, 1942 July 2-1955 November 7 (Box 1268, Folder 6)
    Report containing data and statistics concerning pupils who withdrew from the schools due to civilian evacuation orders by military authorities or in anticipation of such evacuation, Superintendent's War Bulletins and Minutes regarding the La Tuna Canyon fire and forced evacuation of Vinedale Elementary School.
  - Evaluation Services, 1892-2008 (Box 1269, Box 1698, Box 1723, Box 1724, Box 1725)
    Adoptions of Agreements for Evaluation Services, Testing Program Reports, Management and Evaluation Branch Reports, studies, assessments and Annual Board Report excerpts related to the history of pupil and teacher promotion, reading testing, state testing, the Integration program, recommendations for high school improvements based on James B. Conant's report, Finance, correspondence concerning Harry D. Smith's allegations that the Iowa Tests of Educational Development contain subversive communist propaganda, evaluations of learning tests, Summary Reports of X Series Tests in basic facts, knowledges and skills, Report on Recommendations to Promotion Policy, protest and approval correspondence regarding teacher evaluations and Course of Study Outlines.
  - Exhibits, 1936 September 21-1982 February 23 (Box 1270, Folder 1-2)
    Memoranda announcing exhibits of student work at various school sites and locations across Los Angeles.
  - Experts, 1948 December 9-1980 July 7 (Box 1270, Folder 3-6, Box 1271, Box 1272, Box 1273, Box 1274)
    Reports and Communications concerning approval of nonroutine personnel actions and the appointment and election of experts for studies, presentations, examinations, consultant services, evaluations and trainings.
  - Expulsions, 1981 March 2-2003 September 22 (Box 1275)
    Expulsion Report: "Trends In Student Expulsions" and Communications for Expulsion Committee Review concerning student expulsions and expunged records which include identification numbers, education code violations and assignments.
  - Extra Curricular Activities, 1982 November 8-1995 December 1 (Box 1276, Folder 1-2)
    Policies, procedures and surveys concerning student involvement in extra curricular activities.
  - Facilities, 1996 March 11-2008 December 9 (Box 1276, Folder 3-5, Box 1277, Box 1278)
    Facilities Services Division Reports and Communications, Facilities Master Plan, BB Bond Facilities Modernization Strategic Execution Plan, Existing Facilities Strategic Execution Plan (SEP), proposals to amend SEP, New Construction SEPs, Small Business Enterprise Report, Family-School Partnership Program implementation report and Feasibility Studies.
  - Factfinding Reports, 1981 February 9-1992 January 10 (Box 1279, Folder 1)
    Minutes concerning the Board's response to Factfinding Reports and a copy of the October 1991 Report to the Factfinding Panel which was used in the factfinding proceedings for AALA, UTLA and employee bargaining units B, C and D.
  - Federal Aid to Education, 1952-1980 (Box 1279, Folder 2-8, Box 1280, Box 1281, Box 1282, Folder 1-3, Box 1710)
    Reports, Communication and correspondence concerning Educational Acts such as ESEA, Federal funding for educational programs and applications for Federal grants for needy students, schools in poor areas, free and reduced price meals, work study, the Mid Secondary City Schools Project, Adult Education, Project Eighteen, Educational Laboratory Theatre Project, Model Cities Program segments, Greater Watts Model Neighborhood and the East/Northwest Model Neighborhood Education Programs, Bilingual Program and the Summer Program for Economically Disadvantaged Youth (SPEDY).
  - Federal Emergency Mangagement Agency (FEMA), 1994 February 7-2003 December 9 (Box 1282, Folder 4)
    Reports designating Authorized Agents of the District for the purpose of obtaining Federal or State Disaster Assistance, establishing a Special Reserve Fund for FEMA earthquake relief and authorizing acceptance of FEMA grants for seismic retrofit or replacement of various school buildings.
  - Federal Service Center Site - Bell, 2007 April 10-2007 April 24 (Box 1282, Folder 5)
    Authorization to accept and assume title to approximately 13 acres of the Bell Federal Service Center in Bell, California.
  - Federations, 1948-1969 (Box 1711, Box 1283, Folder 1-3, Box 1282, Folder 6-7)
    American Federation of Teachers (AFT) Local 1021 newsletters, open letters, correspondence, bulletins, transcripts of statements to the Board, correspondence concerning Un-American activities, memoranda and petitions on the More Effective Schools Bill, HR 16357.
    AFT College Guild Local 1521 newsletters, insurance benefits information and salary proposals.
    Los Angeles Federation of Teachers Local 430 Communications of protest against the Dilworth Act and the loyalty oath, statement of Board member Eleanor B. Allen concerning the organization's "unsound leadership and questionable activities," "The Los Angeles Teacher" newsletters and a letter to Board President Georgiana Hardy from Local 430 President Harold Orr expressing regret that Board members use teachers as scapegoats at official Board meetings to further their campaigns for election to the City Council.
  - Fees, 1938 June 23-1999 March 23 (Box 1283, Folder 4)
    Summaries of purchase orders, imprest funds and contracts for furnishing equipment, supplies or services to the District, Bulletin regarding physical education towel service fees and inter-office correspondence concerning filing fees for classified examinations and County Clerk fees for printed forms.
  - Films, 1936-1995 (Box 1283, Folder 5-7, Box 1284, Box 1285, Folder 1-7)
    Correspondence of protest against the use of instructional films on the subject of communism, transcriptions of Board discussion on communist films, Division of Instructional Services Bulletin No. SC-38 on Instruction About Communism, petitions requesting a review of the District's "Instruction About Communism" policies and actions, a copy of "audio-visual news" and instructional film catalogs.
  - Fingerprinting, 1936 April 4-1999 May 25 (Box 1285, Folder 8)
    Correspondence, reports and memoranda concerning fingerprinting systems and policies for pupils and employees.
  - Fingertip Facts, 1974-2007 (Box 1285, Folder 9)
    Fingertip fact booklets and pamphlets on the District, including an administrative guide containing a brief history of the Heritage School House, established in 1876 by the Vernon School District and annexed to the LAUSD in 1896.
  - Fire, 1942 September 10-2001July 24 (Box 1286, Folder 1-2, Box 1285, Folder 10-11)
    Reports and Correspondence concerning fire incidents, cooperation with the Fire Department, rules and regulations, emergency procedures, fire prevention, fire protection, fire testing and declarations of emergency for repair of fire damaged buildings.
  - Firearms, 1980-1999 (Box 1286, Folder 3)
    Guidelines for student expulsion, Board rules and regulations, and resolutions concerning school safety and the public's right to school environments free from the fear of gun possession and use.
  - Fireworks, 1980 June 8-1988 May 10 (Box 1286, Folder 4)
    Fireworks safety reminders and reaffirmations of Board Rule 2251 regarding fireworks prohibition.
  - First "5" L.A. (Prop. 10), 2003 January 28-2003 February 11 (Box 1286, Folder 5)
    Proposal to authorize the receipt of the First 5 LA (Proposition 10) $1 million planning grant and delegate authority to implement the grant for seven school readiness centers in May 2003.
  - Flags, 1901-2001 (Box 1286, Folder 6-12)
    Reports and correspondence concerning the raising and lowering of the American Flag, legal rights of students who do not participate in the daily flag salute, origins of the U.S. Flag, complaints against George Washington High School teacher Mr. Haswell Parker, inclusion of "under God" in the Pledge of Allegiance and patriotism.
  - "Focus On Education", 1989-1990 (Box 1287, Folder 1)
    Copies of the Los Angeles Unified School District newspaper.
  - Food Services Branch, 1999 December 14-2007 March 28 (Box 1287, Folder 2-4)
    Business Services Division Food Services Branch Pilot Project Report and Food Services Review in the LAUSD Final Report.
  - Forms, 1954-1971 (Box 1686, Folder 2)
    District forms for the following: Architect's Agreement, Structural Engineering Contract and Fees, Revocable License, Simplified Bid and Contract, Small Size Jobs, L.A. County Uniform Local Sales and Use Tax and Landscape Work.
  - Fort Mac Arthur, 1987 March 30-1998 July 28 (Box 1287, Folder 5)
    Proposals and reports concerning the development of the Fort Mac Arthur Project to facilitate the location and development of educational, scientific and research programs with a major focus on marine related studies.
  - Forums, 1943 November 1-1961 March 2 (Box 1287, Folder 6)
    Committee Reports and correspondence concerning District involvement in forums for educational public discussion.
  - Foundations, 1981-1998 (Box 1287, Folder 7-11)
    Committee reports regarding District agreements with the following foundations: BankAmerica, California Community, Herb Alpert, Pacific Telesis/Pacific Bell and Marine Animal Husbandry.
  - Fraternities & Clubs, 1926-1958 (Box 1287, Folder 12)
    Correspondence, Board rules, California Education Code and regulations regarding unlawful student involvement in off-campus, non-school sponsored and secret clubs.
  - Freedom, 1947-1962 (Box 1287, Folder 13-15)
    Correspondence and Minutes concerning awards presented to schools by the Freedoms Foundation, Inc., founded in May 1949 in Valley Forge, Pennsylvania as a non-profit, non-sectarian, non-political organization to annually award those who do the best job in bringing about a better understanding of the American Way of Life.
    Bulletins and booklets concerning the Freedom Train's visit to Los Angeles, Exposition Park, its cargo containing original documents of American liberty and the District's rededication to American principles.
    Freedom scrolls and propaganda from the Crusade for Freedom, supporting the National Committee for A Free Europe and its striking arm, Radio Free Europe.
  - Freeways, 1942-1990 (Box 1288)
    Correspondence and Committee reports regarding District properties and the following freeways: Santa Monica, Simi, Ventura, Hollywood, Whitnall, Beverly Hills, Century, Glendale (formerly Allesandro), Golden State, Harbor, Olympic, Pomona, Riverside and San Bernardino.
  - Funds, 2003-2008 (Box 1289, Folder 1-3)
    Reports regarding authorizations to make interfund transfers and the establishment of imprest accounts for payment of Division of the State Architect fees.
  - Fund Raising Activities, 1982 November 1-2005 September 9 (Box 1289, Folder 4)
    Documentation of District fund raising drives for various relief campaigns.
  - Future Teacher Preparation Corps, 1989 February 6-1991 March 4 (Box 1289, Folder 5)
    Committee reports concerning the implementation and articulation of teacher preparation options for District students.
  - "G" File, 1936-1955 (Box 1290, Folder 1-2, Box 1289, Folder 6-12)
    Correspondence and attachments pertaining to complaints, investigations of teachers, un-American activities, postwar demands for vocational and technical training, industrial firms employing 50 or more persons in the Los Angeles District, tolerance posters and blotters from the Institute for American Democracy, Inc., a bibliography of selected research studies in educational administration from the University of California, communistic text books, payroll deductions, materials for inclusion in the Time Capsule to be placed in the concrete of the Pershing Square Garage, Code of Ethics for Members of California Teachers Association and alleged communists in the schools organized chronologically by file as follows: G 1305-1454.
  - Games, 1958 May 27-1958 June 12 (Box 1290, Folder 3)
    Correspondence concerning the use of dart games on school premises.
  - Gann Limit, 1999 October 12-2005 January 11 (Box 1290, Folder 4)
    Reports regarding the adoption of the District's Appropriations Limit (Gann Limit).
  - Gavels, 1950 February 20-1977 July 1 (Box 1290, Folder 5)
    Board Minutes from annual meetings during which the outgoing President presents a gavel to the incoming President and the newly elected President presents a gavel hewn from the handrail of the stairs of the old Los Angeles High School by the industrial arts class at Venice High School to the outgoing President as an expression of appreciation for leadership service.
  - Gay and Lesbian Project, 1992 April 20-1994 August 15 (Box 1290, Folder 6)
    Board resolutions regarding the development of a procedure to record and report hate crimes, recognizing June as Gay and Lesbian Pride Month and the adoption of the document, "Educating for Diversity" as policy. The Gay and Lesbian Project was formerly called Project 10.
  - General Maintenance Fund, 1987 June 29-1990 June 28 (Box 1290, Folder 7)
    Reports regarding the Routine Repair and General Maintenance Fund.
  - Gifted and Talented Education Program, 1978 July 10-2004 January 13 (Box 1290, Folder 8-9)
    Reports and bulletins concerning the implementation of gifted/talented program services, polices and procedures for assessment and identification of gifted/talented students, Individual Honors Program, Advanced Placement Program and materials from the District's 30th Annual Gifted and Talented Conference.
  - Gifts, 1949-1983 (Box 1290, Folder 10-13, Box 1291, Box 1292, Box 1293, Folder 1-2, Box 1712)
    Committee reports and acceptance Communications for donations to the District.
  - Governor's Task Force, 1980 October 20-1981 March 20 (Box 1293, Folder 3)
    The District's response to the findings of Governor Brown's special Task Force to examine the fiscal condition of the Los Angeles Unified School District.
  - Grade Level Reconfiguration, 1982-2005 (Box 1293, Folder 4-6)
    Grade level reconfiguration proposals and plans to relieve overcrowding, take advantage of underutilized school sites and prepare for projected enrollment growth.
  - Grading, 1968 May 27-2004 February 24 (Box 1294, Folder 1-2)
    District policies pertaining to grade change appeals, marking practices and procedures, progress report documentation, "C" average policy and grade requirements for participation in extra curricular activities.
  - Graduation Requirements, 1962 January 15-2008 March 27 (Box 1295, Folder 1-3, Box 1294, Folder 3-6)
    Correspondence and reports concerning graduation policies, requirements, implementation of the A-G initiative, revisions and modifications.
  - Grand Jury, 1936-1985 (Box 1295, Folder 4-10)